<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-basketball</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1893-04-01/ed-1/seq-10/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NOW FOR A NEW GAME
Baticing Baae Ball inCaml In
stitute Gyuasuiuu.
A GAME ALL CAN PLAY.
>a"er nianean r @Medsee-A Osmbinmttm
et haswases and feet natI-36e Ned eor
Deun-e.ss-A pset Reeuiring indsabnm
Tse laus ethe Game.
N INDOOR BPORT
which is new to this
city has bees iatre
duced by Mr. MauaI
A. Joyce, the athletic
instructor at the Car
roll Istitute. The
game has met with
great popularity is
other places where it
has been played, and
from the interest which
it hnt excited among
the members of the
Carroll Institute is bids fair to asset with the
Succes here that it bas in other cities. Almost
owery might basket bell is played in the gym
anshetts the institute, and the sport is not only
Smithy and invigerating, but exciting and full
ot interest.
Bushet ball wva Arst started about a year ago
ad ree that time it hes spread throughout
Se esuntry esecially in the gymnasiums of
he yong Men a Christian asociatioss. It is
paticularly adaptable to business men. as little
narmarx A. Joyce.
se metpractice is required to learn it and there
6, no incident roughness if the rules are
stictly adhered to. It is the intention of Mr.
deyce is try to have other teams formed in the
symmasisme in the city and to have regular
entestn between them. It eomameade itself in
s it can be played in almost any sized room
den any had of lot. whether it be large or
mail, and that the number of player. need
only be limt. I b the size of the ground. It
bkings into play all maseles of the body. thus
being a healthy exercise, and at the same time
te a ws incidens to moet sports are want
1. The only apparatus neessary for the
oe to be played is a regular Rugby foot ball
mnd re half-bushel baskets.
movwr rT PL 6TD.
Theegh she courtesy of Mr. Joyce a Stan
aoprter witnessed a game of basket ball played
M the Carrer Institute on one of the evenings
of this week. The two baskets are attached to
th =anig strack at the opposite ends of the
gymmsam and U.s object of the game is to
Shen e heU in the opponent'e basket. The
uame consist of mine men each. made up of a
gaiheeper. two backs to assist him. a center, a
eight and left henter, two forward and a home
ma. They are arranged in this order from
Oe gnal whica they are defending. It is not
asessmry that the players thou!d remain in
teir glaces. but they should move in such a
way as to gie the forward player an oppo:
baesy Is gee a good tos at the goal or the
baecks to keep theer opponents from obtaining
so mmm by taking it from thea when they are
ghbntsto throw. It is the luty of the goal
ba~to beep the ball away fromi the vicinity.
etgoal. end it is more often neessary for
hi to bat the bail with his had tha for
e~er meambers of the seama to do so.
L. Serim. 3. leeward
4.ame.. eae...
4. Sm. .a.5
en.. ...s-....e.
The game is started by the teems lining up
ba their respseutve positions and then the
safeae tomes the ballian the air, It must not be
te.-d antal it strikes the ground. Thea the
players ean catch it. and the object of the one
who obtains it isto pass istso one of the players
ahis own sidec.who either passes itto inotherwho
msay be in a favorable position to tom f~ar goal
or else attempts to auake a goal himself. To
bee a foot bal into a basket euasiended ten feet
a cen SsA.av
beG airani eiasest lags en~t. held it.ie
net en eas messean means, end thee.
thanmy ethe at guat are madebut
as t ase -s eemtl, and e sensty
ohB~in meds. esnammty, an the
qshad esty. The haDeam be aoma
an ists with -n or beth --a-~
In bM the sesm s e 40 -a -e
e be h ss:
asmmmS he es h the det er hased
A , e esms e with te hasb mUs
am thmm... ..a. a. he ... ...
Gotas o ben shile rmaI and Mas to stop
The har maw be held in ds baud The arms
Iee or bod soat not be used for blding it.
If h lb is beld for any length of time th
referee tess it into the air. as in the baegtnmg
of theam
o the5 ein, holding, J~n .trp, n
or striking b allowed. The t iafringem m
'f this rule eosnts a foal and a second dis
q"mli= a player, but, as in foot ball, a substi
tats may take his place.
IN TaN BAsKET. C
When a ball goes out of bounds it is put in
play in the same way as in a foot ball game.
The game consists of two halft of twenty
minutes each or such time as the captains may
decide on. and time is taken out for delays.
A goal counts three points and a foul one
point for the opponent. and a majority of the
points decides the game.
There are a referee and umpire, whose duties
are the same respectively as the same officials
in a foot ball game.
Any player has a right to get the ball at any
time while it is in the field of play. provided
that he handles only the ball and not the op
ponent.
ADVANTAGEs OF THE GAME.
To an observer the game seemed to be one
that will solve the problem, which has been a
knotty one for some time, of introdncing a
game which will meet the excitement incident
to most outdoor sports and at the same time
be suitable for indoor play. At present when
the outdoor season closes most of the athletes
drop tbe sports in which they have been in
terested and the benefits thev derived from
them are lost. This game is one that requires
skill and agility. but strength is not one of the
necessary factors. and, consequently. men of
all physical conditions can take part in it. It
has also been found to have been a useful
sport for girls and women, as it is especially
APTEn THE FALL.
adapted to securing good health without having
the nervous strain caused by some of the
sports now indulged in.
In its principli. it is a combination of foot
ball and lacrosse. It resembles foot ball in
most of the rulings, but in the method to be
pursued to obtain a goal the game more closely
resembles lacrosse. Although at first glance it
would hardly seem possible to have any amount
of team play in the game, still it is only by the
concerted action that a team can play to the
beet advantage. A novice in the game inva
riably feels disposed when he obtains the ball
to make a shot for the goal, which could not be
made from any distance one time in a hundred,
as in order that the ball should remain in the
basket it has to be skillfully and easily tossed,
not thrown. A good player will. when he has
the ball, quickly look for one of his own team
who is in an uncovered position to whom he
can tos it. In this way a well-drilled team
could almost entirely keep the ball from the
hands of a team made up of new men. Quick
ness of eye, hand and foot is one of the first
requisites for a good player, and he also must
keep his head about him. A moment's hesita
tion or a wrong pass may give considerable
advantage to the other side.
If an umpire is chosen who strictly follows
the rules of the game there is little chance for
any roughness, as running with the ball is
prohibited, and thus the injuries coming from
sharp tackling in foot bal are done away with.
The attention of the player is fastened on the
ball and personal feeling in the matter is lost
sight of. The object of each player when one
of his side obtains the ball is to place himself
in an uncovered position so that one of his own
team can pays it to him, while the opponents
should in this eae stick closely to the men
with whom they are paired so that a pass to
them would gave an equal opportunity for each
to catch the ball. It is in this respect that
cool-beadedt.euand quickness count. Idi
vidlual play on the part of one man will destroy
all the good work that the rest of the team may
do. If the game in played indoors in a gym
naisium the passee should be more of a toes
rather than hard straight throw.
As the game has apparently obtained a good
foothold in this city and as it is a healthful and
at the same times exciting sport it is to be
hoped that the efforts of Mr. Joyce to make the
game a popular one in this city will meet with
success, Some of the men under him are bo
conming quite proficient and before long he will
have a iirst-class team,</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82014635/1893-04-21/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>FOE MEN AND WOMEN.
Basket Ball as Playod in Y. M. O.
A. Gymnasiums.For a long1 time gymnasium instruc
tors were confronted by the necessity
for a game which could be played in
doors by old and young, male and fe
male. They wanted a game devoid of
lough features, yet one which should
be thoroughly scientific, and which
should atford plenty of opportunity for
good healthy exercise for the scholar
or business man, and training for the
athlete, feuch possibilities, says the
New York Sun. have been discovered in
the game of basket ball, which has be
come so popular in Fchool and club
fjjnnnasiums throughout thp country.
The (fame was first introduced by the
directors and pupils of the Y. M. C. A.
fill
tSOAI.3.
training school at Springfield, Macs.
Its advantages were t,oon perceived,
and the sport, spread to the gymnasiums
controlled by the Young Men's Chris
tian association, and was further in
troduced in scholastic institutions and
club gymnasiums. At the training school
Ihc g.iuic was developed, and a strong
team was drilled in the simple work
ings of it by James Naismlth, one o the
Springfield instructors, and an earnest
worker in i be Held of all-around sport
and recreation. In New York and
senator lVoui Delii ware to-servo for tha IJrooklyn.are sereral good teams, and
unexpired fl of his original term. H1 P'V "lt; a ir"IU "" w' l-l"ie-
This is the only case cf a father The goals pictured in this col
umn arc iised, the upright one for the
field, on wliich it can be placed at any
point, and the other for Indoor play.
The latter is attached to the gallery or
the wall of the room. The string is
used to turn the goal so that tho ball
may readily be regained. These goals
are the improved article The first
goals, from which the game got its
name, were only peach baskets nailed
to tho wall or running tiack.
The game can be played by a number
of men at once. In a small jrvmnasium.
' howover, flvo aside is the most con-!
In larger rooms nine
men can piay on a biae. Lnis is con
sidered the regular, number, and they
are placed a -hown in the accompany
ing illustration. Tho game itself is
strictly one of passing the ball fiom
man to man. It can neither be kicked
nor batted with the fist. The object is
to get the ball into the basket or goal.
A large person is useful, but one of the
best players it tho Twenty-third
htreet Y. Jf. C. A. gymnasium is
a little hap not much oTerfour feet tail. To get an un
covered position is of the utmost im
portance, as the player can thus easily
get the ball and as easily pass it to one
of his side near the goal. It requires a
great deal of practice to put the ball in
the goal, wliich is placed at some dis
tance above the players' heads. 2Cbt
alone must a pla-or be bkillful, he
must also be very lively. A player
must thiow the ball from the spot
w here ho catches it, but ho can turn
around to throw it. 2vo interference is
allowed, and tackling and pushing are
strictly prohibited. A player may only
obstruct the passage of the bail after it
is thrown.
When the game is played 011 a field
the player may run with the ball if he
continually throws it above his head
and cr.tcho it again. The ball may
also be diibbled along the ground with
the hand.
Tt-.di play counts for everything in
basket play. Tlie t.wo forwards and
the home man should always work to
gether to get the ball into the goal.
The backs guard the goal, and the cen
ter men are supposed to get the ball
and pass it forward toward the home
man.
The game is usually played in two
halves of fifteon minutes each, with a
slight intermission. When a goal is
made the same goes right on. It is
perhaps the ' fastes' game played to
day, and is played with a snap "which
football player in lining up may well</text>
      </result>
	    
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1917-03-03/ed-2/seq-29/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		Basketball Scores
.Illinois 21, Northwestern 12.
Minnesota 31, Iowa 19.
Ohio State30, Indiana 14.
Bowen lights 14, Phillips 9.
Bowen bantams 13, Phillips 13.
.Hyde Park bantams 13, Medill 10.
Crane lights 25, Calumet 19.
Lane heavies 22, St. Ignatius 11. '
Boys' Club 26, La Salle 8.
Seminoles 29, Albany Park 2.
Cornell Cent 32, Hyde Tic "Y" 12
Kildare A. C. 24, Tabor 24.
Dvorak Park 46, Perez 24.
Bethlehem 29, Brentano 22.
Oak Park 21, University High 9.
	</text>
      </result>
	    
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE GIRLS’
BASKETBALL TEAM</text>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn92070146/1920-06-11/ed-1/seq-8/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85053044/1950-03-03/ed-1/seq-9/#date1=1756&index=2&rows=20</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Basketball Tourney
FIRST SESSION, THURSDAY
First Game
Brady . .20. Browning . .53.
Second Game
Oilmont . . 47. Sunburst . . 52.
TONIGHT—Loser of I vs. Loser of 2.
Winner of 1 vs. Valier.</text>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn96060044/1961-08-21/ed-1/seq-7/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BASKETBALL & BOWLING
Marine Barracks Basketball teJtn is
starting to round into good shape
after competing in quite a few pre
season games x^ith the various Dep
artments. The s.eason is scheduled
to open right after Labor Day, and
we hope to be ready for the tough
competition that always prevails in
the Captains Trophy League.</text>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn98060266/1938-01-06/ed-1/seq-2/#date1=1756&index=1&rows=20</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045211/1917-01-26/ed-1/seq-18/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>MISSES CRAMER AND SHARK. TWO OF TEMPLE fagi.'Tr - .' PS " i ; JSiG$H3&raBteidit MNfflffiBHr
UNIVERSITY'S BASKETBALL STARS WC ' '' 'JSffilf " "'' "-Yd MtSW</text>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88077225/1951-08-13/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1756&index=7&rows=20</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TOLEDO, Auk. 13 (I\o)—Uni
versity of Toledo authorities have
allowed two basketball stars in
volved in the recent bribe scandal
to withdraw from s: Uool ra:he
than be expelled.
Dean of Students Donald F.
Parks said the discipline commit
tee recommended lenient action n
recognition of the full coopers*4 lot"1
offered by players Jack Freeman
and Robert McDonald to District
Attorney Frank Hogan of Ne
York City.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
	
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-gettysburg</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1912-11-10/ed-1/seq-12/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
	    
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026089/1913-07-03/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1756&index=1&rows=20</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>“The battle of Gettysburg was the decisive struggle in the greatest war in the
history of the world. It was an astounding exhibition of courage and endurance
on both sides. The fact that only half a century after the men who immortalized
that field by their valor meet in brotherly love is a splendid demonstration of
American generosity. ”</text>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1922-07-16/ed-1/seq-77/#date1=1756&index=2&rows=20</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>"High tide" of the battle of Gettysburg as reproduced by the marines recently, and
showing where so many heroes of the civil war fell. The marines were allowed to fall
"dead" wherever the inclination struck them.
& Ewint.
First photo of the entry of Polish troops into Upper
Silesia, carrying out terms of the plebiscite. Kattowitz, center
of the mining district, was taken over by the soldiers shown
in the photograph.
(c) P. Si A. Photon.
1
The "old jimmy pipe" made its appearance at the Gettys
burg maneuvers. The smokers are Senator Pepper of Penn
sylvania and Gen. Dawes.
rt)lliirri> & Kwitijr.
How the railroad strike ties up trains in the Sunnyside yard of the Long Island railroad.
where 12,000 men walked out.
?p. & a. riiofiM.
The "Tent White House" at Gettysburg, occupied by the
President and Mrs. Harding during their recent stay at Gettys
burg. In the photo are the Governor and Mrs. Trinkle of
Virginia, President Harding, Gen. Dawes, Senator McCormick
and Acting Secretary of the Navy Roosevelt (with back turned
to camera).
?Harris & Ewing.
Firing a three-inch anti-aircraft gun at night during the
Gettysburg sham battle.</text>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82016187/1908-05-28/ed-1/seq-6/#date1=1756&index=3&rows=20</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/45043535/1909-04-01/ed-1/seq-17/#date1=1756&index=5&rows=20</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1949-06-05/ed-1/seq-115/#date1=1756&index=7&rows=20&</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1913-06-28/ed-1/seq-9/#date1=1756&index=10&rows=20</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>UNION HERO OF GETTYSBURG, GEN. SICKLES,
WRITES HIS OWN STORY OF GREAT BATTLE
(Here is Gen. Dan Sickles' own story of the part he played in the de
cisive battle of the war.
The fiftieth anniversary of that battle is to be celebrated at Gettys
burg next week by the reunited union and confederate veterans, and the
leading figure at the reunion will be Gen. Sickles himself, on crutches, 93
years old, the only surviving general who fought on that bloody field.
There he will tell his old comrades, as here he tells Day Book readers,
of the gallant peach orchard fight in which he lost his leg, of his remark
able talk with President Lincoln afterward, and of his friendly adventures
laler in Atlanta with his old Gettysburg enemy, Gen. Longstreet.)
BY MAJ.-GEN. DANIEL E. SICKLES
Copyright, 1913, by The Newspaper EnterprisasAssociation.
. The semi-centennial ceremonies of the battle of Gettysburg appeal with
compelling power to me because of the part which Fate decreed that I
should play in the great conflict, because I left my leg on that bloody field
and because I am the only general of either side who has been spared
through the 50 years that have intervened.
All the others, of both the northern and southern armies, have gone.
I alone, at the age of 93, remain.
I have been asked by the editor of The Day Book to tell how I lost my
leg at Gettysburg, and I am happy to
comply, and I will also tell how I lost
my head at Atlanta thanks to Gen.
Long'street and hot Irish whisky
punch.
I never knew what sort of missile
hit me, but the surgeons believed it
was a fragment of a shell.
I was struck about 6 o'clock in
the evening of July 2, after having
taken my advanced position in the
Peach Orchard and having fought for
hours with the command of Gen.
Longstreet opposite me on the con
federate side, to prevent the enemy
taking the Round Tops which were
just to my left. I was mounted on a
fine black stallion and was standing
under an apple tree when the missile,
flying alongside my horse, struck my
right leg.
It wa&a terrible wound, and pained
me intensely, but it did not knock
me from my horse or make me lose
consciousness, nor did it touch my
horse. I dismounted by myself and
was helped on a litter by my aides.
The report flew up and down my
lines that I had been killed and offi
cers, came running to get the facts.
Gen. Sickles Today.
They reported that my men were
panic-stricken, so I directed my aides
to carry me the whole length of my
lines, that my soldiers might see me.</text>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042242/1916-03-16/ed-1/seq-3/#date1=1756&index=11&rows=20</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1914-03-25/ed-1/seq-12/#date1=1756&index=12&rows=20</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89070012/1951-10-25/ed-1/seq-7/#date1=1756&index=19&rows=20</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Actual Civil War photograph by pioneer photographer Matthew Brady—from “Mr. Lincolns Cameraman" by Roy Meredith
What tan the Battle of Gettysburg
teach us about the UNITED NATIONS?
*ln order to form a more perfect union,” wrote
our founding fathers in 1787.
But between this writing of a Constitution
for the United States and the Declaration of
Independence in 1776, a gap of 11 years had
passed—marked by bickering and dissension
among the 13 original states.
A more perfect union? It wasn’t decisively
welded for at least 78 years—on the fields of
Gettysburg, Antietam, Fredericksburg, Bull
Run. And our states still squabble.
• • •
Yet there are thousands of people who say the
United Nations can’t work — simply because
it hasn’t created Utopia in 6 short years.
F. A. McKinney
BREWERY GULCH GAZETTE
Let’s look at the record...
Your U.N. has already achieved a Charter
and in a far shorter time than we took to
write our Constitution...
The U.N., in its 6 years of existence, has
stopped 3 shooting wars involving the lives
of more than half a billion people.
It helped lift the menacing Berlin Blockade
... it provided food, shelter, and clothing, for
1,575,000 displaced persons ... helped stop a
cholera epidemic in Egypt... trained people
for a greater measure of self-government...
helped build trade, agriculture, science, edu
cation, in “have-not” nations.
You say the United Nations can’t work? Your
great-grandfather could have said the same
thing about the United States!
UNITED NATIONS
WEEK
The United Nations—Our Best
Hope for Peace with Freedom
I</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
	
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-nietzsche</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82015679/1904-01-17/ed-1/seq-25/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
	    
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045774/1921-05-15/ed-1/seq-89/#date1=1756&index=1&rows=20</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The author's approach is stated
clearly and succinctly In the foreword.
The only sane view for the world to
day, she maintains, is that which is
to be f(%nd in the works of Friedrich
Nietzsche. Nietzsche's philosophy may
l<e briefly summed up as follows; Man
is not dominated by the will to live,
as Schopenhauer insisted, but rather
by a smouldering will to power. Man
is not an end in himself, but an in
carnate bridge toward something
greater and finer over which the spir
it may travel. If there is one thing j
that man loves better than life It is
power?power to transcend self and
thus to attain to a nobler estate of
humanity.</text>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85047084/1909-02-07/ed-1/seq-12/#date1=1756&index=3&rows=20</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn92066979/1915-07-09/ed-1/seq-5/#date1=1756&index=4&rows=20&</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>LECTURE AT |
AUDITORIUM
MEMBER OF SUMMER SCHOOL
FACULTY AT CARNEGIE LIBRARY |
BEFORE LITERARY CLUB.
Philosophy and War Discussed by'
Speaker In Connection With Read
ings From Books by Noted German
Savant—Philosophy Taken to Be
Underlying Cause of Present War.
■ I
by W. S. Ingham.
A very interested audience, in which
were a number of ladles, listened last
night to the lecture given before the
Laramie I.lterary club, at the library
auditorium, by Dr. E. P. Turner of the
summer school, upon "Philosophy and
War.”
Dr. Turner's address took the form
of a discussion of the speculative
philosophy of Friedrich Wilhelm
Nietzsche, the German metaphysician,
whose writings are held by many peo
ple to be the foundation of the dom
inant militaristic idea of the German
I nation. In the course of the dlscus
-1 sion, however, which followed the ad
! dress, when answering the many ques
tions propounded to him, Dr. Turner
expressed the opinion that the teach
. Ings of Nietzsche have been no more
read in Germany than in England or
France, and were not the Inspiration
of the war.
Views as to War.
| - It is natural, said Dr. Turner, in
view of the many philosophers that
Germany has produced, that people
should seek for the philosophy which
may be taken as underlying the views
with which the Germans regard the
war.
The conception of Neitzsche that hu
man life in the mass is negligible, and
that what we know as morals is but
the remains of needs which the human
race experienced in its early struggles
to sustain itself, lends color to the as
sumption that such philosophy under
lies present German thought.
That the idea of the "superman,”
sustaining himself by standing upon
the backs of the masses, and justified
by the “spectacle of powerful living”
or “the will to power” as being the
object and consummation of humanity,
might be taken as the attitude of owhole nation, wag elicited from the lec
turer during the course of the ques
tions answered, and ho also allowed
that the philosophy of Neitzsche may
be construed as a consistent defense
of war.
Only Expression of Beliefs.
In summing up the metaphysical
teachings of Neitzsche, Dr. Turner
said that his philosophy is only an ex
pression, stated more fairly and more
powerfully than ever before, of be
liefs which the world has always'held,
and which may be found in other forms
in the teachings of Plato and Aristotle
and even in those of Schopenhauer and
Carlisle.</text>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn92073229/1962-10-31/ed-1/seq-13/#date1=1756&index=5&rows=20</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>FRIEDRICH NIETZSCHE
G 34 Philosophy $2.95</text>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn92066928/1926-02-24/ed-1/seq-5/#date1=1756&index=6&rows=20</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>These two books illustrate a con
trast. The philosophy of Nietzsche
is that of an excessive individual
ism. It is the bald confession of
the ruthless law of the survival of
the fittest. He tells us that it is
all nonsence to talk of giving our
selves for the sake of others. He
insists that we must yield to the
evitable law of selection.</text>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020274/1903-12-09/ed-1/seq-16/#date1=1756&index=8&rows=20</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>SAYS NIETZSCHE'S VIEWS
ON LIFE ARE REMARKABLE.
Professor Frank Thllly Lectures on
Philosophy Before Washington
I Diversity Association.
Professor Frank Thllly lectured last
evening before the Washington University
Association on the philosophy of Friedrich
Nietzsche, He said, in part:
"There is a central thought running
through Nietzsche's entire work, a stand
ard or Ideal that Is the key to his phil
osophy of life, and enables us to under
stand this remarkable thinker and his op
position to our times.
"The desire for power is, according to
him. the fundamental liumin instinct, the
fundamental human fact. The goal Is the
production of a higher type of men, of a
race of heroes.
"Life la impossible without battle. It Is a
struggle for existence. Hence, war is pre
ferable to peace. Indeed peace is a symp
tom of decaj. a sign of death. War and
struggle are hard, of course; they bring
out the i sterner elements in man; they
cannot bei. carried on without Injury, pain
and suffering, without hurting the weak
and feeble,
"But since all these thlnes are Inevita
ble, since no strong race ran be produced
without the desire for power, which im
plies war, struggle, pain, suffering and In
jury to the weak, they arc good and their
opposltes bad.
"We must Inflict injury; we must suiter
our ptin because it is unavoidable. We
are not here for our happiness, we are
here to hold our own, to assert ourtelves
or to go down.
"It is true that life la terrible, but that,
according to Nietzsche, lq no reason for
pessimism. Indeed, pessimism Is impossi
ble except In a disease and degenerate
race, for .the desire for life Is too strong
In a healthy mind to bo terrified by pain
and battle.
"Our traditional morality Is also rejected
by Nletzscho because it is baed on -pity
nnd favors the weak against the strong.
Religion, too, particularly Christianity, is
repudiated for the same reason; it preach
es false values, self-denial, svmpathy,
peace, other worldllness, nonrcslstance,
equalltv ; it is the religion of the weak and
exhausted."
Professor Arthur O. Lovejoy of the chair
of philosophy of Washington University,
will deliver two lectures before the aspo
rtation at university chnpel To-morrow
night he will speak on "The Morals of
rorelgn and Colonial Policies; a New
Pioblem for Ethics." The subject for the
second lecture, December 17. will be "Tho
Moral "Standard In International Rela
tions." , Los Anarclcs Tourist Sleeper
Via Wabash" Line</text>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn99063957/1916-01-14/ed-1/seq-8/#date1=1756&index=9&rows=20</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82016014/1905-12-02/ed-1/seq-13/#date1=1756&index=11&rows=20</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042354/1905-12-02/ed-1/seq-6/#date1=1756&index=12&rows=20</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
